Vitor Lima

Full Stack Developer, Aspiring Data Scientist







+55 (12) 988 111 393



+55 (12) 996 494 913



github.com/vitorjclima



vitor.lima@msn.com

Skills



Interests

Software Development

Cloud Computing

Performance Metrics

Data Mining

Artificial intelligence

Languages -

Portuguese

English

French

Spanish

Programming -

Over 5000 lines

- · Java: Spring, Hibernate, JUnit, Easy-Mock, RESTful, Gradle and Maven
- SQL: MySQL and Oracle
- · C, Shell and Robot Framework

Familiar

 Spring MVC and Boot, OSGi, Camunda BPMN, Cassandra, Postgre, Hadoop, HTML, ZooKeeper, Akka, WildFly, and Tomcat.

Profile

I have a degree in Computer Science from Federal University of Sao Paulo (UNIFESP), where I was constantly in touch with statistics, data analysis and artificial intelligence. Also, at UNIFESP, used to speech about software development with Java and Python. I has experience with artificial intelligence algorithms over big data into a chemical company. Where he also got in touch with Lean six sigma. Recently, I am working in a Telecom System to take more experience with big systems, big data, design patterns, frameworks and work with a global team. Working daily with clusters, continuous integration and continuous improvement. Finally I had put some efforts into learning Tableau and Spring.

Work Experience

Mar 2017 -Present

Software Developer

FITec - Technological Innovations

- Working in the development of a system for accountability of telecommunication industry with multinational agile teams;
- Java developer in Ericsson RM solution. Revenue Manager is an evolution of existing Ericsson's billing and charging solution. It's a converged, cloud-ready billing and charging system that redefines the role of the BSS. It is a real-time system, configurable, open, modular and automated system.

I am working specifically at Finance TPG (Technical Product Group). Financial assets of a customer in a back-

- Due to the size and modularization of this system, practices such as Test First TDD (Test Driven Development), code review, continuous integration, deployment and support of DevOps are indispensable.
- Java Developer in the BSCS billing solution part of the CBiO Ericsson product. Responsible for the analysis and correction of TRs (Trouble reports).
- Main technologies: Java EE, OSGi architecture, Karaf, Kafka based messaging, JUnit, REST Interface, Camunda BPMN, JSON, Hibernate, Cassandra, EasyMock, Mockito, Oracle SQL, Robot Framework, Unix, Git, Jenkins, and Gerrit.

Aug 2006 -Jun 2016

Chemistry Technician and Data Analyst using Neural Network

ICL Brazil

Monsanto Company

- Interaction of the course of computer science to the area of chemical and physical-chemical analysis through development of software for the management of chemical, physicochemical analysis, and software for standardization and automation of laboratory labels. The calibration module for this project is open source and is available on my GitHub;
- Data mining of DeltaV and SAP for neural network implementation (MLP) to train the chemical reaction control system, thus minimizing operational waste;
- · Automation in the emission of documents through parameterization of QM (Quality Manager) module SAP
- · Analysis of food phosphates, as well as characterization of these salts in unknown mixtures;
- Development of methods using high precision titrators, liquid chromatography (HPLC) and ionic (IC), spectrophotometry, laser particle analysis, and atomic absorption;
- Preparation and adaptation of laboratories for ISO 9001, 22000 and 17025 and OHSAS 18001.
- Main technologies: Instrumental Analyses, Neural Network, Artificial Intelligence, Minitab, SAP, statistical calculations (Linearity, Grubbs Test, Standard Deviation, among others).

Feb 2006 -Aug 2006

- Production and analysis of several salts of phosphates in laboratory scale; Development of new analytical techniques, reducing the analytical time and minimizing the expense of reagents, using microdroplets in titration analyses and automation of chemical and physicochemical analyses using automatic titrators and high-performance chromatography (HPLC).
- Main technologies: Instrumental Analyses, Minitab and SAP.

Academic Experience

2015 - 2016

Maritaca Project Sao Jose dos Campos, Sao Paulo, Brazil

Intern

UNIFESP - Federal University of Sao Paulo

- The goal of this work is studied scalability, since concepts of Cloud Computing. That includes realizing studies about virtualization tools, load balancing, web servers, distributed file systems, and others subjects. Were studied differents performance metrics for evaluating the models, such as response time, capacity, and efficiency of the system in general.
- Main technologies: Linux Server (Ubuntu and Cent-OS), Java, Big Data, Cloud Computing, Load Balancer (Nginx and HAProxy), Bash Script, Cassandra, Virt-Manager, KVM and Performance Metrics.

2012 - 2014

Free Software Education Program

Sao Jose dos Campos, Sao Paulo, Brazil

UNIFESP - Federal University of Sao Paulo

UNIFESP - Federal University of Sao Paulo

- Responsible for scheduling and presenting lectures about open source environment, about how to create a fastest Java System (systems that do not need maintenance).
- Main technologies: Linux (Ubuntu, Fedora and Cent-OS), Java, Netbeans, Maven, My SQL and Git.

Education

2008 - 2015

Bachelor, Computer Science

Sao Jose dos Campos, Sao Paulo, Brazil

Specialization: Data Mining and Artificial Intelligence

2003 - 2005

Technician, Chemistry

Lorena, Sao Paulo, Brazil Specialization: Instrumental Analysis

Courses

Six Sigma Yellow Belt

6sigmastudy.com

USP - Technical College of Lorena

Jul 2017

Scrum Fundamentals Certified

SCRUMstudv.com

Sep 2016 -

Dec 2016

General English

ILAC - International Language Academy of Canada

Sep 2017

License Number 584264

License Number 585471

Vancouver, Canada

Pre-Advanced English Certificated